

Faruk Dube

Doctoral Student

My Contact

farukmeddie@gmail.com

+46 76 409 28 47

https://ruqse.github.io

Faruk Dube

Education

- Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Sweden, 2019-Present PhD in Biomedical Sciences
- Uppsala University, Sweden, 2016-2018
 Masters of Medical Science in Infection
 Biology, Biological and Biomedical Sciences
- Makerere University, Uganda, 2009-2012
 Bachelor of Science in Biomedical
 Laboratory Technology

Wet lab skills

- PCR-based techniques
- ELISA
- Bacterial, Viral, fungal and C. elegans culture
- DNA/RNA handling
- Sequencing library preparation

Computer skills

- NGS data analysis (Genome and Transcritpome)
- · Pipeline building with Nextflow
- Data wrangling and visualisation
- Statistics
- · Programming in R, Python and Bash
- Unix
- Git
- Illustration in Inkscape

Language

- Luganda (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Swedish (Beginner Intermediate)
- Swahili (Intermediate)

About Me

Data-driven infection biologist interested in utilizing both lab work and computational resources to solve biological/medical problems. I have previously worked with viruses, fungi, bacteria, and now parasites. Currently, I am a doctoral student utilizing both wet-lab and bioinformatics techniques to understand why parasites are resistant to available drugs.

Professional Experience

PhD candidate | Swedish University of Agricultural Science 2019/10 - Present

Activities:

- Thesis "Ivermectin-induced gene expression changes in adult Parascaris univalens and Caenorhabditis elegans- a comparative approach to understand and control threatening anthelmintic resistance"
- Worm culture and drug exposure experiments
- RNA handling
- Primer design and RT-qPCR
- Transcriptomic data analysis and visualisation
- · Manuscript writing
- Two scientific studies published

Research Engineer | National Veterinary Institute 2018/07 – 2019/10

Key responsibilities:

- Bacteria and Fungi culture and DNA handling
- DNA library preparation, sequencing, genome analysis
- Building NGS data analysis pipelines
- Provide bioinformatics support to different projects
- · One scientific study published

Laboratory Technologist | Makerere university-Walter Reed Project 2013/04 - 2016/08

- Key responsibilities:
- Virus culturing
- Sample and RNA/DNA handling
- PCR- and ELISA-based assays
- · Training interns

Awards

2022 Travel grant-SLU

2022 Travel grant-Foundation Alfa Laval AB's (AB Separators) fund

2021 Travel grant - SLU

2020 Stiftelsen Gösta och Sonja Engströms fond

2016 Swedish Institute Study Scholarship for a two-year masters studies in Sweden